Even though I know he
can't possibly be here...
I wonder what Haruto-san is doing right now.
Um, what did Oniichan say?
Well, if I remember correctly...
It was "Mii-chan."
What?
Mii-chan. That's what Haru-kun used to...
But luck like that just doesn't happen.
Now, focus. Focus!
Good morning, Miharu.
Good morning!
You're practicing first
thing again this morning.
You really are a hard worker, Miharu.
Do you think so?
You really are!
Is there some reason you
work as hard as you do?
What? Well, it's partly
because it's fun, but...
But?
But while we're living peacefully,
Haruto-san is out there working
hard. I suppose that's why.
That makes sense!
It's all for Mister Rio!
No, it's... I just don't want
to be a burden for Haruto-san.
Yes, indeed.
If that means that you learn
Spirit Arts more quickly,
I'd say it's a good thing, isn't it?
Right?
Yes.
Still, it's already amazing that you can
create water after such a short time.
But you were even able to control
it just now, weren't you?
I was shocked!
Miharu, you're connected to
Lady Aishia telepathically,
so it's possible that allows your Spirit Arts
abilities to bloom with more strength.
What?
Yes, indeed!
But the results are all due to the
hard work you've put in, Miharu.
Of course!
Yes!
Thank you.
But... I see.
When I get home,
I'll have to thank Ai-chan.
Aishia!
Please have some tea.
All right.
It's delicious!
It tastes similar to when Haruto makes it.
Does it? Well, I did teach Rio
how to make it, after all.
The wind's picking up.
Is something wrong, Aishia?
No, it's nothing.
Spirit Chronicles 2
M-Monsters?
Wh-Why are they wearing knights' uniforms?
Time to modify some humans.
The Clutches of Evil, Stealing Ever Closer
Who are you?
Halt!
Yes, yes.
Are you adventurers from Amande?
No, we're not.
You seem an unsavory sort.
If you're not adventurers,
what are you doing here in the forest?
That's because we are, in fact, unsavory.
And would you gents be knights
of the Beltrum Kingdom?
How do you know that?
Well, when you consider which knights
are staying in Amande at the moment...
you'd be the elite guards assigned
to Princess Flora, right?
Who are you really?
I have some minor business with you gents.
There look to be twenty of them.
And they're all young.
Now that I think of it...
Huh?
You were once a noble of the Beltrum Kingdom.
Is there anyone here you recognize?
No. And even if there were,
it wouldn't change what we have to do.
As you seem to have no objections
to using them as blank dolls.
I'll leave it to you.
This is too much trouble! Why don't we
just beat them up and restrain them?
W-Wait! We should talk until—
We've got a lively one here!
I like it.
Please be careful not to kill them.
I know! But I'm helping you out here,
so let me have a little fun.
You just stay on your guard to
make sure none of them escape.
It seems he's of the same mind!
Let me do this!
No!
We'll surround and subdue them.
If they resist, then you
may counterattack, but...
R-Ready yourselves!
Too slow.
The moment I move to draw my sword,
you should be strengthening
yourselves with magic!
This is the perfect prey for me!
I'll kill him and leave that blasted duke
who made a fool of me flabbergasted!
You're an interesting one, aren't you?
You can die! Enchant Physical Ability!
I'll save you for last.
Come on! How about all of you hurry up
and strengthen yourselves with magic, too!
E-Enchant Physical Ability!
You have permission to kill him!
As long as we have the one
in the hood, that's enough!
Really?
Then go ahead and try!
What's wrong? Is that all you've got?
Let me have a little more fun, won't you?
Blast it!
Come on! You haven't hit me once!
He's looking down on us!
He's just playing around!
I suppose I should start
reducing their numbers.
Now it's my turn to attack. Right?
Th-This isn't possible.
At this rate, we'll lose.
The way he moves...
Is that an enchanted sword?
Everyone and their enchanted swords!
The sneaky cowards!
If I had an enchanted sword, then...
Four left, I see.
I-Impossible.
Thanks to you, the retrieval of the
unconscious knights is proceeding smoothly.
Just a little more work to
finish things off, then.
And that means it's nearly your turn.
R-Run!
R-Retreat!
Th-This is for help!
We need to call for help!
It's a tactical retreat!
Maybe the fight wasn't enough
for them to understand
the difference in our physical abilities.
Hey!
If you run, it just means
I'm going to come catch you!
H-Hey!
H-How did you get here?
Don't worry. I'm not going to kill you.
Blast it!
As promised, you're the last one.
Now don't cause too much trouble, all right?
I was right. I like that look in your eyes.
What?
I get a glimpse of the dirty way
you've lived in those corrupt eyes.
Maybe, just maybe, you know?
W-Wait! If it's money you want, I'll pay!
And I won't tell anyone what you've done!
Huh? Money?
I've got him! I can use money to negotiate!
You really are an interesting one.
Spirit Chronicles 2
Thank you for coming today.
I will send a messenger
to you at a later date.
I hope that you will be able
to enjoy some leisure time
during your stay here in Amande.
Yes, thank you.
If, um...
Yes?
If we should ever happen to meet again
somewhere, I hope we will have time to talk.
We would like to offer our
formal thanks to you as well.
If you would do us the honor.
Of course. I'd be happy to.
Is it as I thought and she has
noticed something about me...
or is this just the sort of girl she is?
I suppose I'll wait and see for now.
Well, we'll be staying in Amande until
we can secure the safety
of the neighboring lands,
so if you'll be visiting Liselotte's mansion,
there'll be chances to see each other again.
Yes, it's just as the Hero says.
If you'd like, I could
arrange for a tea party.
Sir Haruto, what do you think?
Yes, if you'd be so kind as to invite me,
I will attend with pleasure.
Yes, I would like that very much, too!
Then, let's leave that for another
time and let the man leave already.
Indeed. We cannot keep him here forever.
Well then, Haruto, let's meet again.
Yes, Your Grace.
Then, I shall see you all another day.
If you'll excuse me.
Is something the matter, Sir Hiroaki?
Huh? What do you mean?
You seem less spirited,
so I wondered if you might
be worrying over something.
No, it's not like anything
in particular is wrong.
And Flora's acting more
oddly than I am, isn't she?
What?
Am I acting oddly?
Oh, so you're not aware of it yourself, huh?
Ever since the monster attack—
no, ever since that guy showed up—
you've seemed fidgety,
like your mind is on other things.
I-I don't think that's true at all.
Well, if you say so, then that's fine.
That's how it looks to me is all I'm saying.
Um, how exactly does it look to you?
Well, you were staring at the
guy's face the whole time, right?
Oh, um... do you mean Sir Haruto?
Oh, so you know that when I say
"the guy," I'm talking about Haruto, huh?
What? Oh, no, I...
Princess Flora is our
kingdom's representative.
Since he saved us from peril,
I'm certain she's worrying over
how to express our gratitude.
After all, it seems Duke Huguenot
is looking to scout him as well.
Oh, that makes sense. Is that what it was?
Y-Yes.
Well, if that's how it is, then
it's not like I don't understand,
but Haruto, huh?
I feel like everyone's making a
little too much fuss over him.
That's because you are simply
too amazing, Sir Hiroaki.
For average people like us,
he is quite incredible enough.
Oh, that makes sense! So that's what it was!
In that case, I suppose I can't blame anyone.
It's done.
Thank you for all your hard work.
I've already begun things here as well.
M-Monsters?
Wh-Why are they wearing knights' uniforms?
Wh-What are they?!
Time to modify some humans.
I'm remaking their
spirits and their bodies.
Lucius, if you wouldn't mind,
please remove their clothing.
Taking a guy's clothes off isn't something
I'm interested in. Do it yourself.
Dear, dear.
Now, why have you left him conscious?
Test it out on him. The perfect
revenant thing you've mentioned.
I think he's got the makings of it in him.
If it fails, a precious
stone will have been wasted.
What's it going to hurt? You're going
to strengthen the rest of them, right?
With the pieces you already have,
that's more than enough fighting power, right?
I suppose I have no choice.
Up you go!
L-Let go of me! Stop this!
Now, let's see...
It doesn't hurt, does it? You see,
I'm not hurting your physical body.
For both your body and mind,
the pain starts now.
It will take a little time.
The search party hasn't returned?
Could that mean that a monster
beyond the scope of our imaginings
hides in the forest?
It's also possible that they've
simply suffered some accident.
I see. You may go.
I will send a notice as to
how this will be dealt with.
Yes, Your Grace.
As I thought, we are in need of someone
talented in our military affairs.
Young Alphonse was part of that unit,
but he seems to have been as
talentless as I suspected.
I wonder if my behavior was
really that unusual today.
What is it that I'm trying to do anyway?
Rio. Haruto.
Their names are different and
their hair colors are different.
They should be two different people.
But if Sir Haruto really is Sir Rio...
Please, take him and get away from here!
Back then, he saved me,
but I couldn't thank him.
I couldn't even undo the misunderstanding.
I couldn't do anything.
Do I apologize?
Even though I've done things that no amount
of apologizing would atone for?
My deepest apologizes.
I should have sent my own people for this.
No, it was I who said that the
advance units for the investigation
should be made up of local knights.
But...
We haven't yet confirmed
that they have all perished.
Let's change our focus.
Thank you. I would like to send another
unit after them with all haste, but...
Yes. In that case,
let's wait until after sunrise.
The possibility that they will come
strolling back in the morning yet remains.
Yes.
Still, I had thought that the earlier battle
had taken care of most of the monsters.
Yes.
There were a few monsters
who fled into the forest,
but I don't want to consider the
possibility that that wasn't all of them.
Does this mean that there are
still minotaurs out there?
Possibly.
If we consider the worst case scenario,
it's possible that even more terrible
monsters are hiding out there.
If there are that many monsters out there,
they wouldn't ordinarily be overlooked.
But it's preconceptions like that
which have led us to this situation.
In that case, I will send Aria.
I will select other capable individuals
from my attendants and soldiers
and lend them enchanted swords.
Good. I would like to offer
a few knights, but—
No, Your Grace.
I cannot ask your people to take
any further action on my behalf.
We will handle what comes next.
I understand.
In that case, there's Haruto.
I think it would be a good idea
to ask for his assistance.
Yes.
If he were an adventurer from Amande,
it would be easier to ask this of him,
but Sir Haruto is a regular citizen.
And among his companions, there seems
to be someone he is protecting.
You're right.
In situations like these, it is adventurers
whom we should be depending upon.
Yes, but in this case, I will
not be using adventurers.
Since there is a strong possibility
that minotaurs remain,
I want to leave preparations in place
in case Amande is attacked unawares.
That would be our greatest worry.
That last specimen should have
completed the assimilation by now.
That's fine!
But having the rest of them thronged around
us is stifling! Put them away already!
Oh, but as they're a new collection,
I wanted to keep them out to
admire for a while longer.
As always, you have creepy tastes
don't agree with me in the least.
Well, they are like my own children.
At last! That feels so much better.
Now I'll be able to sleep in peace.
We move tomorrow morning.
Everything is set up for just before sunrise.
Please don't oversleep.
If you're worried about oversleeping,
tell it to our newest member over there.
Right?
In that case, before those useless
louts fully acclimatized,
I should have gone alone and
taken care of everything myself.
What a creepy voice.
That is a perfected revenant.
It's more aggressive than
the strengthened forms,
and it has greater fighting abilities,
but its lack of logic and the
awkward remains of its intelligence
render it harder to control.
But it'll be useful in the
attack tomorrow, right?
Yes. It will, indeed.
As a piece to be used and discarded.
I have high hopes for you, Alphonse!
Here you go!
I'll kill them! I'll kill all of them!
You're eating the bone, too?
Guess there's no hope for you, huh?
Haruto, wake up.
Aishia?
Morning.
Good morning. We have an emergency.
What's happened?
Monsters have suddenly appeared nearby.
I can sense them.
Inside the city? Or are they outside?
I can't tell their specific location.
But they're to the west.
Their presence feels all jumbled, so I
think there are probably a lot of them.
What?
With a presence this strong, I should
have noticed them sooner... but I didn't.
I think things have probably
been strange since yesterday.
Do you see people on the road?
People?
We did get a notice saying that the
knights who went to explore the forest
might return.
All right.
For now, let's go and get a
better grasp of the situation.
Where's the professor?
She's still asleep.
I see.
Have the knights returned?
Monsters!
Sound the bell!
Next Time
The Battle to Defend Amande
"The Battle to Defend Amande."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Illustration: Minazuki Futago